Ian Stuart Meyers

32 Jeremy Hill Road, N. Stonington, CT 06359

Competent, organized and detail oriented individual with multi-state real estate management experience and excellent computer and communication skills. Able to comprehend, analyze, and interpret complex financial

information for effective presentation to clients, supervisors, and business partners.

PROFICIENCIES AND SKILLS

- Financial Analysis and Modeling: cash flow models, IRR analysis, discounted cash flow valuations, financial statements, capital expenditures, lease analysis, NPV analysis, and budget variance reporting.
- Marketing, Research and Analysis for real estate acquisitions, development or dispositions in CT, RI, VT and FL.
- Lease Analysis and Negotiations with complex landlord/tenant lease arrangements.
- Vendor Contracts and Relationships: bid evaluation, contract reviews, compliance, and cost analysis.

EDUCATION

University of Connecticut | School of Business

May, 2016

Cell: (860) 961-9630

Email: ianstuartmeyers@gmail.com

Bachelor of Science: Finance, Minor in Real Estate

EMPLOYMENT

Property Manager - Robert & Lori Bantle, Greenwich, CT

2013-Present

- Managed real estate investment portfolio located in CT, RI, VT and FL. Analyzed and evaluated residential and commercial properties for purchase or disposition. Effectively interacted with clients, legal counsel, and property agents to obtain necessary data to accurately prepare financial pro-forma analysis and perform investment financial calculations.
- Collaborated with property owner and vendors to create acceptable budget for property capital improvements, repairs, and maintenance.
- Project manager for major structural and interior property renovations. Oversaw architect, construction team, and interior designer in accordance with construction timeline, approved budget, and client expectation.

Real Estate Manager – Latimer Point Properties, Stonington, CT

2009-Present

- Responsible for management of 4 income-producing multi-unit properties located in New London County, CT
- Ensured that properties were properly maintained, insured, and 95% tenant occupied.
- Updated and analyzed balance sheets, income and cash flow statements. Reported marketing and financial data timely and accurately. Participated and counseled business partners in decisions related to investment property acquisitions, dispositions, and capital improvements.
- Managed tenant acquisitions, credit review, lease executions, billing and collections of rents, and responded to tenant and property issues in a timely and professional manner.

Assistant Business Manager - High Street Yoga, Westerly, RI

2010-2013

• Negotiated vendor contracts and commercial leases for two new locations for improved revenue and reduced expenses. Supervised 18 teachers, employment contracts, weekly profit reporting, P&Ls, and cash flow analysis.

Buyer & Jr. Sales Associate - Seaport Studios, Westerly, RI

2008-2010

• Responsible for retail sales for 3 locations including merchandising, display, advertising, and product pricing. Assisted in payroll and back office operations.

<u>COMPUTER SOFTWARE:</u> *Financial Analysis:* DCF Modeling, Bloomberg; *Microsoft Office Suite:* Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook, Access; *Business Software:* Point of Sale, Constant Contact, QuickBooks